Ciaran Carson papers, circa 1970-2010
Emory University
- Writings by Carson, circa 1970-2009, Series 2; Boxes 8-28, 48-59; OP1-5
  - Poetry, 1971-2009, Subseries 2.2; Boxes 12-18, 50-54; OP 1-2
    - Collected poems 1973-2009, Subseries 2.2a; Boxes 12-16, 50-54; OP1
      - "Four Sonnets," MS and TS [variant title for sonnet No. 1: "Early Days" and "Sonnet"; for sonnet No. 3: "The One Before the First One"; for sonnet No. 4: "Number Three"] (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - "From the Welsh," MS and TS [1972-1993] (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - "Grass," MS and TS (Box 14, Folder 15)
      - "Latitude 38 S," MS and TS [variant titles: "Down Under," "To Orpheus," "Flak Jacket"] [See also Subseries 2.3: After Ovid, "Down Under," corrected galley proofs] (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - "On Not Remembering Some Lines of a Song," MS and TS (Box 14, Folder 17)
      - "Opus 14," MS and TS (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - "Opus Operandi," notes, MS and TS (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - "Ovid: Metamorphoses, V, 529-550,"TS [See also Subseries 2.3: After Ovid, "Ascalaphus" corrected galley proofs] (Box 14, Folder 20)
      - "Ovid: Metamorphoses, XIII, 439-575," TS with notes by Tess Gallagher [See also Subseries 2.3: After Ovid, "Hecuba" corrected galley proofs] (Box 14, Folder 21)
      - "Ovid: Metamorphoses, XIII, 576-619," [See also Subseries 2.3: After Ovid, "Aurora and Memnon" corrected galley proofs] (Box 14, Folder 22)
      - "Second Language," TS (Box 14, Folder 23)
      - "Second Nature," MS and TS [includes MS in Irish of Seán Ó Ríordáin's "Malairt," dated Christmas 1995; verso contains MS copy of Emily Dickinson's Poem 465, "I heard a fly buzz"] (Box 14, Folder 24)
      - "Sonnet," MS and TS (Box 14, Folder 25)
      - "Tak, Tak," MS and TS (Box 14, Folder 26)
      - "Tak, Tak," proof for TLS publication, 31 September 1993. (Box OP1, Folder -)
      - "Two to Tango," TS (Box 14, Folder 27)
      - First Language, table of contents; list of drafts from Carson's folders (Box 14, Folder 28)
      - First Language, corrected TS [self-bound] (Box 14, Folder 29)
      - First Language, corrected TS with comments by Tess Gallagher and ALS, 13 September 1993 (Box 14, Folder 30)
      - First Language, jacket galley proof, with ALS from Peter Fallon (Box 14, Folder 31)
      - First Language, corrected proof (Box 14, Folder 32)
      - Letters from the Alphabet (1995)
      - Letters from the Alphabet, corrected typescript (Box 14, Folder 33)
      - Opera Et Cetera (1996)
      - "Alibi"
      - "Alibi," MS and TS [See Subseries 2.3: When the Tunnels Meet] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "Bird," MS and TS [See Subseries 2.3: When the Tunnels Meet] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "Cortege," MS and TS [See Subseries 2.3: When the Tunnels Meet] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "Me and My Cousin," MS and TS [See Subseries 2.3: When the Tunnels Meet] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "The News," MS [See Subseries 2.3: When the Tunnels Meet] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "A Pair," TS [See Subseries 2.3: When the Tunnels Meet] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "The Poet as Snow-Merchant," MS and TS [See Subseries 2.3: When the Tunnels Meet] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "Siege," MS and TS [See Subseries 2.3: When the Tunnels Meet] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "The Words," MS and TS [See Subseries 2.3: When the Tunnels Meet] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "Opera"
      - "Hotel," MS (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - "Papa," TS (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - "Zulu," TS (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - "Opera," MS [sequence contents; list of dedications] (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Opera Et Ceter a, research materials (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Opera Et Cetera, notes and word lists [homophones and etymologies] (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Opera Et Cetera, corrected typescript [self-bound] (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Opera Et Cetera, corrected typescript with letter to Peter Fallon, 4 January 1996 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Opera Et Cetera, corrected proof (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Sport, corrected proofs of poems from "Opera" in Opera Et Cetera, with TLS from Fergus Barrowman, 13 February 1996 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - The Twelfth of Never (1998)
      - "1798," TS [variant title: "Eglantine"] (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - "1998,' TS (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - "Adelaide Halt," TS (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - "The Ambassadors," TS (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - "The Arterial Route," TS [variant titles: "Artery", "Zen Archery"] (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - "Banana Tree," TS [variant title: "Banana"] (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - "Banners," TS (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - "Belladonna," TS (Box 15, Folder 18)
      - "The Blue Shamrock," TS (Box 15, Folder 19)
      - "Catmint Tea," TS [See also Series 1: Correspondence, August 28, 1998, from the Chicago Review] (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - "Clonmel Jail," TS (Box 15, Folder 21)
      - "Con Script," TS [variant title: "Conscript"] (Box 15, Folder 22)
      - "Crack," TS [variant title: "Hemp"] (Box 15, Folder 23)
      - "Dancers," TS (Box 15, Folder 24)
      - "Digitalis," TS (Box 15, Folder 25)
      - "The Display Case," TS (Box 15, Folder 26)
      - "Drops of Brandy," TS (Box 15, Folder 27)
      - "Envoy," TS (Box 15, Folder 28)
      - "Fairground Music," TS [variant title: "Ghost Train"] (Box 15, Folder 29)
      - "Fear," TS (Box 15, Folder 30)
      - "February Fourteen," TS (Box 15, Folder 31)
      - "Found," TS (Box 15, Folder 32)
      - "From the Horse's Mouth," TS (Box 15, Folder 33)
      - "Fuji Film," TS (Box 15, Folder 34)
      - "The Groves of Blarney," TS [variant title: "Glockamorra"] (Box 15, Folder 35)
      - "Hippocrene," TS (Box 15, Folder 36)
      - "The Irish Exile Michael Hinds," TS[variant titles: "Michael Hinds", "The Irish Exile"] (Box 15, Folder 37)
      - "Jarrow," TS (Box 15, Folder 38)
      - "Heart of Oak," TS (Box 15, Folder 39)
      - "Legions of the Dead," TS (Box 15, Folder 40)
      - "Let Erin Remember," TS (Box 15, Folder 41)
      - "The Lily Rally," TS [variant title: "Mouth Music"] (Box 15, Folder 42)
      - "Lir," TS (Box 15, Folder 43)
      - "The Londonderry Air," TS (Box 15, Folder 44)
      - "Lord Gregory," TS (Box 15, Folder 45)
      - "Milk of Paradise," TS [See also Series 1: Correspondence, August 28, 1998, from the Chicago Review] (Box 15, Folder 46)
      - "Mountain Dew," TS [variant title: "Diminuendo"] (Box 15, Folder 47)
      - "Mustard," TS (Box 15, Folder 48)
      - "Nine Hostages," TS (Box 15, Folder 49)
      - "No Tengo Mas Que Darte," TS (Box 15, Folder 50)
      - "Paddy's Knapsack," TS [variant title: "Sergeant Bourgogne's Knapsack"] (Box 15, Folder 51)
      - "Picador," TS (Box 15, Folder 52)
      - "Planxty Miss Dickinson," TS [variant title: "It"] (Box 15, Folder 53)
      - "Planxty Patrick Connors," TS (Box 15, Folder 54)
      - "The Poppy Battle," TS (Box 15, Folder 55)
      - "The Rising of the Moon," TS (Box 15, Folder 56)
      - "The Rising Sun," TS (Box 15, Folder 57)
      - "Saké," TS (Box 15, Folder 58)
      - "Salt of the Earth," TS (Box 15, Folder 59)
      - "Sayers, or, Both Saw Wonders," TS [variant title: "Sayers"] (Box 15, Folder 60)
      - "Sod of Death," TS (Box 15, Folder 61)
      - "Spenser's Ireland," TS (Box 15, Folder 62)
      - "Spot the Wallop," TS [variant title: "They Seek Him There"] [See also Series 1: Correspondence, August 28, 1998, from the Chicago Review] (Box 15, Folder 63)
      - "Spraying the Potatoes," TS [variant title: "Blue Potato Spray"] (Box 15, Folder 64)
      - "Sunderland and Spencer," TS (Box 15, Folder 65)
      - "The Tailor's Twist," TS (Box 15, Folder 66)
      - "Tib's Eve," TS (Box 15, Folder 67)
      - "The Tobacco and Salt Museum," TS (Box 15, Folder 68)
      - "Trooping the Colors," TS (Box 15, Folder 69)
      - "Twelfth Day," TS (Box 15, Folder 70)
      - "Wallop the Spot," TS [variant title: "And Did You See My Love?"] (Box 15, Folder 71)
      - "Who Ploughed the Lowlands Low," TS [variant title: "Blue and True"] (Box 15, Folder 72)
      - "The Wind that Shakes the Barley," TS (Box 15, Folder 73)
      - "Wolf Hill," TS [note: this typescript was included with "drafts" of The Alexandrine Plan] (Box 15, Folder 74)
      - "Wrap the Green Flag Round Me," TS [variant title: "Hannibal Crossing the Alps"] (Box 15, Folder 75)
      - "The Year of the French," TS [variant title: "Under the Pyramids"] (Box 15, Folder 76)
      - "Yellow," TS (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - The Twelfth of Never, typescript "First Draft" with corrections (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - The Twelfth of Never, typescript with corrections and commentaries by Carson and Peter Fallon (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - The Twelfth of Never, typescript with corrections and commentaries by Tess Gallagher, with TLS 30 January 1998 and 1 February 1998 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - The Twelfth of Never, typescript with corrections and commentaries by Tess Gallagher, [See also Series 1: TLS from Gallagher 5 April 1998] (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - The Twelfth of Never, galley proofs (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - The Twelfth of Never, galley proofs (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - The Twelfth of Never, cover image [Picador] (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - The Ballad of HMS Belfast (1999)
      - The Ballad of HMS Belfast, research materials [clippings] (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - The Ballad of HMS Belfast, draft of table of contents (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - The Ballad of HMS Belfast, photocopies of poems from published volumes (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - The Ballad of HMS Belfast, corrected proofs (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - The Ballad of HMS Belfast, cover image [Picador edition] (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - Breaking News (2003)
      - "Belfast," TS (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - "Blink," TS (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - "Breaking," TS [variant titles: "Alert," "Stop," "News"] (Box 50, Folder 9)
      - "Campaign," TS (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - "Detail," TS (Box 50, Folder 11)
      - "Edward Hopper: Early Sunday Morning, 1930," TS (Box 50, Folder 12)
      - "The Forgotten City," TS (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - "Francisco Goya: The Third of May 1808, 1814," TS (Box 50, Folder 14)
      - "The Gladstone Bar circa 1954," TS (Box 50, Folder 15)
      - "Harvest," TS (Box 50, Folder 16)
      - "Home," TS (Box 50, Folder 17)
      - "Horse at Balaklava, 1854" (Box 50, Folder 18)
      - "The Indian Mutiny," TS [variant title: "Lucknow"] (Box 50, Folder 19)
      - "In St. Patrick's Cathedral, Dublin," MS (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - "In St. Patrick's Cathedral, Dublin," TS, February 2002 (Box 50, Folder 20)
      - "Last Effect," TS (Box 50, Folder 21)
      - "Minus," TS and notes (Box 50, Folder 22)
      - "News," TS [variant titles: "After," "Press," "Breaking"] (Box 50, Folder 23)
      - "Shop Fronts," TS [variant title: "Chemist, Tobacconist"] (Box 50, Folder 24)
      - "Siege," TS (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - "Skip," TS (Box 50, Folder 25)
      - "Some Uses of a Dead Horse," TS, 22 January 2002 (Box 50, Folder 26)
      - "Spin Cycle," TS (Box 50, Folder 27)
      - "Spin Cycle 2" [see "Spin Cycle"] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "Théodore Géricault: Farrier's Signboard, 1814," TS (Box 50, Folder 28)
      - "War," TS (Box 50, Folder 29)
      - "The War Correspondent," TS and notes, 23 June 1999-2 July 1999 (parts 1-7) [incorporated into Breaking News January-February 2002] (Box 50, Folder 30)
      - "Waste Not," TS (Box 50, Folder 31)
      - "Wire," TS (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Breaking News, TS ["first round"] with commentaries by Tess Gallagher and Carson's responses; also includes ALS from TG to CC (11 February 2002), TLS from CC to TG (19 February 2002) (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - Breaking News, TS ["second round"] with commentaries by Tess Gallagher and Carson's responses; also includes TLS from TG, 5 March 2002 (Box 16, Folder 17)
      - Breaking News, TS ["third round"] with commentaries by Tess Gallagher; also includes APCS, 25 March 2002 (Box 16, Folder 18)
      - Breaking News, TS, fair copy, circa 2002 (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - Breaking News, page proofs, 16 January 2003 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Breaking News, proofs from Wake Forest, February 2003 (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - Breaking News, table of contents and notes, 2001-2002 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - Breaking News, blurb, no date (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - For All We Know (2008)
      - "L'Air du Temps," Part Two, TS (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - "The Assignation," Part One, TS and notes [variant titles: "Wenceslas" and "Under Cover"] [see also "Reboubt," Part One] (Box 51, Folder 8)
      - "The Assignation," Part Two, TS (Box 51, Folder 9)
      - "Before," Part One, TS [variant title: "Swap"] (Box 51, Folder 10)
      - "Collaboration," Part One, TS and notes [variant title: "Résistance"] (Box 51, Folder 11)
      - "Corrigendum," Part One, TS [variant title: "Hotel Scribe"] (Box 51, Folder 12)
      - "Corrigendum," Part Two, TS (Box 51, Folder 13)
      - "Fall," Part Two, TS (Box 51, Folder 14)
      - "From Your Notebook," Part One, TS (Box 51, Folder 15)
      - "From Your Notebook," Part Two, MS and TS (Box 51, Folder 16)
      - "Hotel del Mar," Part Two, TS (Box 51, Folder 17)
      - "In the Dark," Part Two, TS (Box 51, Folder 18)
      - "Never Never," Part One, MS and TS (Box 51, Folder 19)
      - "Never Never," Part Two, TS (Box 51, Folder 20)
      - "On the Contrary," Part One, TS [variant title: "Apples in Winter"] (Box 51, Folder 21)
      - "On the Contrary," Part Two, TS (Box 51, Folder 22)
      - "Pas de Deux," Part Two, TS (Box 51, Folder 23)
      - "Prelude and Fugue," Part One, MS (Box 51, Folder 24)
      - "Prelude and Fugue," Part Two, TS (Box 51, Folder 25)
      - "Proposal," Part Two, TS (Box 51, Folder 26)
      - "Redoubt," Part One, TS [with manuscript of "The Assignation"] (Box 51, Folder 27)
      - "Redoubt," Part Two, TS (Box 51, Folder 28)
      - "Revolution," Part Two, TS (Box 51, Folder 29)
      - "Rue Daguerre," Part Two, TS (Box 51, Folder 30)
      - "Second Hand," Part One, TS (Box 51, Folder 31)
      - "Second Hand," Part Two, TS (Box 51, Folder 32)
      - "Second Take," Part One, TS (Box 51, Folder 33)
      - "Second Take," Part Two, TS (Box 51, Folder 34)
      - "Second Time Round," Part One, TS [variant title: "A Couple of Words"] (Box 51, Folder 35)
      - "Second Time Round," Part Two, TS [variant title: "A Couple of Words"] (Box 51, Folder 36)
      - "The Story of the Chevalier," Part Two, TS (Box 51, Folder 37)
      - "The Story of Madame Chevalier," Part Two, TS (Box 51, Folder 38)
      - "Through," Part Two, TS and notes (Box 51, Folder 39)
      - "To," Part One, TS (Box 51, Folder 40)
      - "Treaty," Part One, TS (Box 51, Folder 41)
      - "Treaty," Part Two, TS [variant title: "On the Contrary"] (Box 51, Folder 42)
      - For All We Know, correspondence, July-August 2006 (Box 51, Folder 43)
      - For All We Know, TS, numbered fragments from Part One (Box 51, Folder 44)
      - For All We Know, TS, numbered fragments from Part Two (Box 51, Folder 45)
      - For All We Know, TS with commentary from Tess Gallagher, 15 May 2007 (Box 51, Folder 46)
      - For All We Know, TS, circa April-May 2007 (Box 51, Folder 47)
      - For All We Know, TS, June 2007 (Box 51, Folder 48)
      - For All We Know, TS, 27 June 2007 (Box 51, Folder 49)
      - For All We Know, TS, circa August 2007 [incomplete] (Box 51, Folder 50)
      - For All We Know, TS, "Part 1" (Box 51, Folder 51)
      - For All We Know, TS, "Part 2," 29 August 2007 [incomplete] (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - For All We Know, TS, 6 November 2007 [1 of 2] (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - For All We Know, TS, 6 November 2007 [2 of 2] (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - For All We Know, TS, "First Fair Copy" (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - For All We Know, proofs from Wake Forest, December 2007 (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - For All We Know, proofs from Gallery Press, 8 December 2007 (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - For All We Know, proofs from Gallery Press, circa 2008 (Box 52, Folder 7)
      - For All We Know, table of contents and notes (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - For All We Know, blurb (Box 52, Folder 9)
      - On the Night Watch (2009)
      - "As Arrows," TS (Box 52, Folder 10)
      - "As I Was Saying," TS (Box 52, Folder 11)
      - "As a Siren Wails," TS (Box 52, Folder 12)
      - "Ask Not," TS (Box 52, Folder 13)
      - "At Binsey," TS (Box 52, Folder 14)
      - "At the Interface," TS [variant title: "At the Intersection"] (Box 52, Folder 15)
      - "Aubade," TS (Box 52, Folder 16)
      - "Behind the Screen," TS (Box 52, Folder 17)
      - "Bells Sound," TS [variant title: "Midi"] (Box 52, Folder 18)
      - "Blip & Echo," TS (Box 52, Folder 19)
      - "Break Time," TS (Box 52, Folder 20)
      - "But Still," TS (Box 52, Folder 21)
      - "The Clock," TS (Box 52, Folder 22)
      - "Come In," TS (Box 52, Folder 23)
      - "Come What May," TS (Box 52, Folder 24)
      - "Euphrasia," TS (Box 52, Folder 25)
      - "The Floor," TS and notes [variant title: "Urlár: a Gloss 2"] (Box 52, Folder 26)
      - "From in Behind," TS (Box 52, Folder 27)
      - "From the Larynx," TS (Box 52, Folder 28)
      - "From His Pedestal," TS (Box 52, Folder 29)
      - "Globe of Death," TS (Box 52, Folder 30)
      - "Holding On To," TS (Box 52, Folder 31)
      - "How Long," MS and TS [variant title: "Practice"] (Box 52, Folder 32)
      - "I Ask Myself," TS (Box 52, Folder 33)
      - "I Looked into That," TS (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - "I Met Him Yesterday," TS (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - "I Remember," TS (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - "I Tell You," TS (Box 53, Folder 4)
      - "I Tried to Get You," TS (Box 53, Folder 5)
      - "In Babylon," TS (Box 53, Folder 6)
      - "In Braille or Morse," TS (Box 53, Folder 7)
      - "In Parenthesis," TS (Box 53, Folder 8)
      - "It Is," TS [variant title: "Insomnia"] (Box 53, Folder 9)
      - "It's Called Needles," TS (Box 53, Folder 10)
      - "The Knife," TS (Box 53, Folder 11)
      - "Let Us Go Then," TS (Box 53, Folder 12)
      - "Matins," TS (Box 53, Folder 13)
      - "My Head Cocked," TS [variant title: "Head Count"] (Box 53, Folder 14)
      - "My Plummet," TS [variant title: "With My Plummet"] (Box 53, Folder 15)
      - "On the Examination Table," TS (Box 53, Folder 16)
      - "On Going," TS (Box 53, Folder 17)
      - "Operation Imminent," TS (Box 53, Folder 18)
      - "The Other," TS [variant title: "All-Clear"] (Box 53, Folder 19)
      - "The Pips Were On," TS (Box 53, Folder 20)
      - "The Ploughman Sings," TS (Box 53, Folder 21)
      - "Rank," TS (Box 53, Folder 22)
      - "The Reckoning That Is," TS (Box 53, Folder 23)
      - "Remembering Being," TS [variant title: "Tap"] (Box 53, Folder 24)
      - "She Belongs To," TS (Box 53, Folder 25)
      - "Siren," TS (Box 53, Folder 26)
      - "Snow," TS (Box 53, Folder 27)
      - "The Storm Without," TS (Box 53, Folder 28)
      - "Stumbling," TS (Box 53, Folder 29)
      - "There Was," TS (Box 53, Folder 30)
      - "This Bullet," TS (Box 53, Folder 31)
      - "This Cauldron," TS (Box 53, Folder 32)
      - "This Device," TS (Box 53, Folder 33)
      - "To Get to the Dark," TS (Box 53, Folder 34)
      - "Transfixed," TS (Box 53, Folder 35)
      - "The TV," TS (Box 53, Folder 36)
      - "Upon Seeing You," TS (Box 53, Folder 37)
      - "Were I to Add," TS [variant titles: "Sum" and "School"] (Box 53, Folder 38)
      - "What Then," TS (Box 53, Folder 39)
      - "With My Head on a Stone," TS (Box 53, Folder 40)
      - "X Marks the Spot," TS (Box 53, Folder 41)
      - "Yesterday," TS (Box 53, Folder 42)
      - "You Gave Me," TS (Box 53, Folder 43)
      - "You Know the Code," TS (Box 53, Folder 44)
      - On the Night Watch, TS, 12 July 2008 (Box 53, Folder 45)
      - On the Night Watch, TS, 15 July 2008 (Box 53, Folder 46)
      - On the Night Watch, TS, "Drafts" (Box 53, Folder 47)
      - On the Night Watch, TS, "First Fair Copy" (Box 53, Folder 48)
      - On the Night Watch, TS, "Second Fair Copy" (Box 54, Folder 1)
      - On the Night Watch, TS, early sequence [beginning with "From in Behind"] (Box 54, Folder 2)
      - On the Night Watch, TS, numbered fragments, circa July 2008 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Uncollected poetry, 1971-2007, Subseries 2.2b; Boxes 16-18, 54; OP2
      - "An Accident at the Mill," TS [originally found with series 5, Belfast Group worksheets, 1971-1972] (Box 16, Folder 19)
      - "According to Luke," TS [included with The Twelfth of Never materials] (Box 16, Folder 20)
      - "After Mallarmé," [originally found with series 5, Belfast Group worksheets, 1971-1972] (Box 16, Folder 21)
      - "Alexandria," TS and notes (Box 54, Folder 4)
      - "Alphabet City," MS (Box 16, Folder 22)
      - "Athlone Through Hilversum," TS, 20 February 2001 [originally filed by Carson with materials from Breaking News] (Box 54, Folder 5)
      - "The Angel," TS (Box 16, Folder 23)
      - "Aranmore Island" (with three sections entitled "Erratics," "The Fault," and "American Wake"), TS [See Series 5: Belfast Group Worksheets] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "Armada," TS [note: one TS included with "drafts" of The Alexandrine Plan, and another with The Twelfth of Never] (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - "Ass," TS (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - "At the Poetry Reading," MS and TS (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - "At the Zoo," TS [originally filed by Carson with materials from The Lost Explorer] (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - "Au Contraire," TS [originally filed by Carson with materials from For All We Know] (Box 54, Folder 6)
      - "Babel," TS (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - "The Battle of Königgrätz," TS, 21 December 2001 [originally filed by Carson with materials from Breaking News] (Box 54, Folder 7)
      - "Beauty," MS and TS [originally filed by Carson in Belfast Confetti notebook No.1] (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - "The Belfast Hospital for Sick Children," TS [circa 2000-2002] (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - "A Bible Dictionary," TS [originally filed by Carson with materials from For All We Know] (Box 54, Folder 8)
      - "Bid," TS (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - "Blitz," TS[originally filed by Carson in Belfast Confetti notebook No. 1] (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - "Breaking the Seal," TS [originally filed by Carson with materials from The New Estate] (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - "Bricriu," TS (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - "The Brother," MS [originally filed by Carson with materials from The New Estate] (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - "Calfskin," TS [early TS found in Belfast Confetti notebook No. 2] (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - "Camphor," TS [originally filed by Carson with materials from For All We Know] [variant title: "In Belfast"] (Box 54, Folder 9)
      - "Candy Apples" and "Directions," MS (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - "Cars swish by like wind," MS [haiku] (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - "Cat and Mouse," TS (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - "Centaurs," TS (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - "The Changeling," TS (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - "C.K. Williams Reading Intro," TS, 28 October 2004 (Box 54, Folder 10)
      - "Claude Monet, The Thames Below Westminster, 1871," TS (Box 54, Folder 11)
      - "The Clockwork Pigeon" TS [See Series 5: Belfast Group Worksheets] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "Colmcille's Vision of Paradise," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: "To Margaret" in The New Estate; originally filed by Carson with materials from The New Estate] (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - "Cushendall Haiku," TS (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - "Cut by a knife so sharp I didn't feel the pain" TS [originally filed by Carson in Belfast Confetti notebook No. 3] (Box 17, Folder 21)
      - "Dandelion Wine," TS [included with The Twelfth of Never materials] (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - "The Death of Acteon," TS [circa 2000-2002] (Box 17, Folder 23)
      - "Directions" [See Subseries 2.2: Uncollected Poems, "Candy Apples"] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "The Drill-Bit Broke," TS [originally filed by Carson with materials from On the Night Watch] (Box 54, Folder 12)
      - "The Eclectic Bar," TS (Box 17, Folder 24)